Paul Ramsey Swift

256 Belfast Dr · Charleston, SC 29407 · (478) 919.0100 · paulrswift@yahoo.com

Highly motivated associate experienced in managing complex projects in front end web development, customer service, human resources, and sales. Excels in fast-paced, deadline-driven environments. Detailed self-starter able to multi-task projects simultaneously. Offering core competencies in:

JavaScript

Backbone

Project Management

Account Management

Oral Presentations

Cisco Desk Agent

Team Work

Salesforce

inContact

Customer Service

HIPPA Compliance

Microsoft Office

Education

Bachelors of Business Administration

Georgia College and State University, Milledgeville, Georgia

Front End Engineering

The Iron Yard, Charleston, SC

September 2016 - December 2016

- Used JavaScript, J Query, HTML, CSS, SCSS, React, Backbone, Bootstrap, Wordpress ES5, and ES6
- Practical use of restful APIs concept
- Successfully worked on multiple team projects with developers who have different skill sets

Career Experiences

Benefitfocus

September 2013 - September 2016

Configuration Consultant

- Worked within strict SLAs to renew insurance carrier plans
- Worked in team setting to find alternative solutions to define boundaries of the problem/request

Team Lead, Benefit Support Center

- Interpreted business requirements from customers into written specifications
- Performed regular training sessions of software and software support techniques
- Participated in weekly client conference calls, distributes takeaways to team members

Benefit Administrator, Approvals Specialist

- Approved qualified life events within Benefitfocus software by verifying documentation
- Produced daily task report to be provided to client

Application Consultant

- Carrier, Administration, and Member IT support/website navigational assistance
- Initial point of contact; 90% first pass resolution, 60+ calls daily

The Blood Alliance

September 2011 - August 2013

Account Manager

- Oral presentations and public relation events to civic and business associations
- Delivered remote and onsite training sessions of software

State Farm, Jeff Cain Agency

January 2011 - September 2011

Insurance Sales Specialist

- Provided a high level of product knowledge to best service policy holders
- Primary contact for policy holders. Responded in a timely, friendly and efficient manner

Easterlin Pecan Co and Pearson Farm

July 2010 - January 2011

Logistics Management/Purchasing Agent

- Supervised loading of shipments; 5-7 per day
- Produced daily inventories, productions and shipping manifests

Wonderland Co LTD.

February 2009 - March 2010

Instructor. Deagu, South Korea

- Taught English to 35+ Korean students/supplemented English to 11 Korean Instructors
- Assisted fellow team members to meet weekly curriculum and reporting deadlines